<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Sulav Timilsina</title><link>http://sulavtimilsina.github.io/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Sulav Timilsina</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sulavtimilsina.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nepali Language Modeling using RoBERTa</title><link>http://sulavtimilsina.github.io/projects/nepali_language_model/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sulavtimilsina.github.io/projects/nepali_language_model/</guid><description>Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers (BERT) is a transformer-based machine learning technique for natural language processing (NLP) pre-training developed by Google. It is at its core a transformer language model with a variable number of encoder layers and self-attention heads. Here we used RoBERTa model wish is also based on BERT with 12 encoder layers. It builds on BERT and modifies key hyperparameters, removing the next-sentence pretraining objective and training with much larger mini-batches and learning rates.</description></item><item><title>Single Image Super Resolution Using Wasserstein Distance</title><link>http://sulavtimilsina.github.io/projects/sisr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sulavtimilsina.github.io/projects/sisr/</guid><description>SISR(Single Image Super-Resolution) is an application of GAN. Image super-resolution is the process of enlarging small photos while maintaining a high level of quality, or of restoring high-resolution images from low-resolution photographs with rich information. Here the model’s work is to map the function from low-resolution image data to its high-resolution image. Instead of giving a random noise to the Generator, a low-resolution image is fed into it. After passing through various Convolutional Layers and Upsampling Layers, the Generator gives a high-resolution image output.</description></item><item><title>Mero Health</title><link>http://sulavtimilsina.github.io/projects/mero_health/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sulavtimilsina.github.io/projects/mero_health/</guid><description>Despite the development of technology the general people are unable to utilise its benifitis in health sector properly. So we developed an Android App which is a complete one stop solution for patient&amp;rsquo;s appointment, medial record keeping, payment and recomendation of doctors/physicians according to the symptoms they are having. We tried to co-relate the patients&amp;rsquo; symptoms and their preferences with the type of doctors they need to visit.
About App: Following are the technical specifications of our app.</description></item><item><title>Nepali Sign Language Classification</title><link>http://sulavtimilsina.github.io/projects/nsl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sulavtimilsina.github.io/projects/nsl/</guid><description>This is a capstone project completed in short amount of time. There arent any data availabe for Nepali Sign Language till now. So I tried to generate small sized data myslef and train various clasifier to accurately detect the hand gestures related to nepali alphabets.
Media Pipe is used for real time hand detection. An image of hand gesture is clipped out from the bounding box of hand which is in-turn fed to the pre-trained model for classification.</description></item></channel></rss>